Blades, Rubén. Rubén Blades recordings and papers: Guide AWM Spec Coll 100
Eda Kuhn Loeb Music Library
- Series I. Audio and audiovisual recordings, 1968-2010; 6 boxes; 6 boxes.
  - Subseries 4. Audiovisual recordings on videocassette, Boxes 5-6.
    - Live in Panama, Patria Entera, Balboa Stadium, live concert, 1999-12-31; 1 videocassettes
    - Maestra Vida Bellas Artes, Puerto Rico, "Escenas"
    - Making of Sun City, 1985; 1 videocassettes
    - Maestra Vida, theater production, directed by Bruce Quinn, in Panama, amateur video, 1997; 1 videocassettes
    - Michelle Frances and Estefani
    - New Year's Eve, live outdoor concert in Panama, television, 2002; 2 videocassettes
    - No Te Duermas
    - Omnivision News Segment on Rubén Blades
    - On the Edge: Improvisation in Music
    - Patria 30 Patria 60 Kodak
    - "Pedro Navaja" drama Puerto Rico, 1985
    - "Pedro Navaja" Rubén Blades in Venezuela (possibly from Amnesty International)
    - Politically Incorrect
    - "Puerto Rico"
    - Puerto Rico Dice Adios a Tite Curet (donated by Rubén Blades), 1 videocassettes
    - Resumen de Noticias, 1994-04-13-1994-12-31
    - Resurrection Blvd. "Verguenza" #312
    - Return of Rubén Blades
    - Rubén Blades and Seis del Solar with Willie Colon
    - Rubén Blades appearance on the David Letterman Show (excerpt); performs an early version of The Hit, 1985; 1 videocassettes
    - Rubén Blades concert at Prospect Park, Brooklyn (donated by Rubén Blades), 2001-7-14; 1 videocassettes
    - Rubén Blades interview on 60 Minutes, (donated by Rubén Blades), 1986-2-16; 1 videocassettes
    - Rubén Blades interview on CBS News Sunday Morning (donated by Rubén Blades), 2003-10-5; 1 videocassettes
    - Rubén Blades interview on Court TV "Hollywood at Large," (donated by Rubén Blades), 2002-12-6; 1 videocassettes
    - Rubén Blades Live Show with Seis del Solar
    - Rubén Blades on Latino TV show with family [poor quality]
    - Rubén Blades, Sessions at W. 54th; live in Baltimore, MD, 1999-09-25-2020-07-15; 1 videocassettes
    - Ruben/Martin Testimonios
    - Rubén Blades: The Early Years, 1993-1994
    - Rubén Blades, various, including parts of Gideon's Crossing; Politically Incorrect; Puerto Rican televised concert [poor quality], 1992; 2000; 1 videocassettes
    - Rubén Blades, various: Live in Panama; Puerto Rico; New Haven, CT, 1999-2002; 1 videocassettes
    - Rubén Blades with Willie Colon, Concierto en La Carlota, Venezuela, (donated by Rubén Blades), 1998-9-15; 2 videocassettes
    - Salsa Electorale a Panama: Le Retour de Rubén Blades [NTSC]
    - "Sicarios" song video
    - The Bronze Screen: A Presentation Reel
    - The Capeman Adventures, (donated by Rubén Blades), November 1997-March 1998; 1 videocassettes
    - The Capeman, theater production, copy of poor audience video, some television coverage, 1998; 1 videocassettes
    - The Capeman, Closing Night Show, (donated by Rubén Blades), 1998-3-28; 1 videocassettes
    - The Palladium When Mambo Was King
    - "Tras la Tormenta"
    - TV Appearances by Rubén Blades: Winson Festival, Bio Intro
    - UC Berkeley - Chicano Studies Graduation
    - UN Goodwill Ambassador Press Conference
    - Visit a Garvin School, 1982
    - WGBH La Plaza, 2003-03-25
    - WNET City Arts Afro-Cuban Groove
- Series II. Periodicals, 1964-2011; 5 boxes; 5 boxes.
  The arrangement is chronological. Oversized issues are housed separately in designated boxes, as noted in the entries below.
  - Life Magazine, [Oversized], 1964-1-24
    Article on the Panama riots
  - Latin NY, no. 18, September 1974
    Cover text and photos: Fania All Stars Live
  - La Musica Iberoamericana (Japan), 1977
    Review of Willie Colon presents Rubén Blades
  - Crawdaddy, March 1977
    Article, 30 Latins Over Tokyo, by Greg Mitchell
  - Resumen, 1977-9-4
    Section on salsa
  - TeVe Guía, 1977-9-24-1977-9-30
    Article, Rubén Blades Ha Dado Nueva Vida a la Salsa, by Sara
  - Swing Latino, año 1, no. 1, October 1977
    Cover text and photo: Rubén Blades: Un Abogado Con Sabor, and article, Mi Familia, by Phidias Danil Escalona
  - TeVe Guía, 1978-3-11-1978-3-17
    Article, Rubén Blades Ha Roto con los Estereotipos de la Salsa, by Sara
  - Downbeat, 1978-11-2
    Salsa 78 - Crossover or Die, about the Fania All-Stars
  - Swing Latino, año 2, no. 15, 1979
    Cover text and photo: Rubén Blades: El Poeta de Latinoamérica, and article, Rubén Blades: El Poeta de la Salsa, by Hugo Adames
  - Swing Latino, año 2, no. 16, 1979
    Cover text: Rubén Blades, Hector Lavoe e Ismael Miranda: ¡Triunfadores! (Blades article missing)
  - Swing Latino, año 2, no. 17, 1979
    Article, El El Show de Rubén y Willie Colon los del Patio se Consagraron
  - Latin N.Y., vol. 2, no. 2, February 1979
    Cover text, photo and article, Heart Throb Rubén Blades: Superman of Salsa, by Anne Saxon
  - TeVe Guía, 1979-2-17-1979-2-23
    Cover photo and article, "El Travoltismo": No Tumbará la Salsa, by Helga Garcia
  - Latin N.Y., vol. 2, no. 4, April 1979
    Several articles, including, Siembra: A New Era for Salsa, by Agustin Gurza
  - Salsa, año 1, no. 1, 1979-4-1
    Cover photo and article, Rubén Blades: ¿Es o No un Revolucionario?, by Wanda Colon
  - Artistas, año 2, no. 21, 1979-4-30-1979-5-13
    Article, Rubén Blades Fue Santero, by Mary Qadir
  - Artistas, 1979-5-24-1979-5-27
    Cover text: Rubén Blades Revela la Verdad de 'Paula C' y Pedro Navaja, interview
  - Latin N.Y., vol. 2, no. 5, May 1979
    Article, Las Estrellas de Fania Desenbarcan en Cuba, by Roberto Gerónimo
  - Estampas, 1979-5-20
    Cover text and photo: Rubén Blades: El Mayor Éxito de Música Latina en Venezuela, and article, Rubén Blades: "Pedro Navaja" Visita Caracas, by Manolo Olalquiaga
  - Folletón, June 1979
    Article, Rubén Blades: Me Inspire en la Vida de los Barrios para Escribir Pedro Navaja
  - Variedades, 1979-6-4
    Cover text and photo: Pedro Navaja Conquisto a Miss Venezuela, and article, "El Pedro Navaja de Rubén Blades: Conquistó a Miss Venezuela, by Atamaica Nazoa
  - Salsa, no. 4, July 1979
    Article, Fania Extiende la Salsa
  - El Cancionero de Estrellas, no.5, August 1979
    Collection of lyrics to songs sung by Blades
  - Down Beat, 1979-8-9
    Blades listed in critics poll results under "Composer, established"
  - Ahora, no. 4, September 1979
    Cover Photo and article, Si No Existiera la Muerte la Vida Sería Algo Tan Normal como un Aguacero, by Tamara Herrera
  - Latin N.Y., vol. 2, no. 9, September 1979
    Article, Que Pasa: Miranda Ataca a Blades, by Roberto Gerónimo
  - Nuestro, vol. 3, no. 8, September 1979
    Article, Salsero with a message, by Rubén Rosario
  - Latin N.Y., vol. 2, no. 10, October 1979
    Blades review in article, The Greatest Salsa Show on Earth
  - New York, 1980-6-23
    Photo of Blades in article on Roberto Duran, The Greatest Street Fighter, by Pete Hamill
  - Latin N.Y., vol. 3, no. 7, July-August 1980
    Cover Text and article, Studio 54: Another Door Opens to Salsa and Latinos, But Rubén Blades' Speech Causes Controversy and Heated Arguments, by Izzy Sanabria
  - Latin N.Y., vol. 3, no. 11, November 1980
    Cover text and photo, "Rubén Blades' New Message," and article, Rubén Blades: Singer, Poet, Philosopher, by Izzy Sanabria
  - Salsa, año 2, no. 18, 1981
    Centerfold poster and article, Rubén Blades No Se Piensa Casar
  - Telerevista (El Mundo), 1981-1-18
    Cover text and photos, "Compango a Base de Realidades," and article, Rubén Blades: Lleva "Maestra Vida" al Teatro, by Migdalia Santiago
  - Coralibe, February 1981
    Article, Rubén Blades: "Gabo y Sanchez me Influenciaron, by David Sánchez Juliao
  - SoHo News, [Oversized], 1981-4-1
    Cover photo and article, Not Just Salsa's Golden Boy, by Enrique Fernandez
  - Diálogo Social, año 14, no. 136, July 1981
    Cover headline and article, ¿De Poeta a Dramaturgo de Salsa?: Rubén Blades: Maestra Vida, by Julio V. Mont Alvo del Valle
  - Latin N.Y., vol. 4, no. 12, 1981
    Cover text and photo, "Willie and Rubén," and article missing (pages removed), Salsa Rebels Speak, by Adela Lopez
  - Rock Express, [Oversized], 1982
    Untitled interview with Blades
  - Salsa, año 2, no. 24, 1982
    Article, Salsa Con Clave
  - Artistas, June 1982
    Article, El Gobierno de Panamá Nombra a Rubén Blades ¡Diplomatico en la O.N.U.!, by Lourdes Calcagno
  - Pensamiento Critico, June-July 1982
    Interview, Rubén Blades-Conversando, by M. Pérez, Osvaldo García
  - Vea, 1982-7-11-1982-7-17
    Article on Roberto Blades, Su Hermano le Aconseja, by Helda Ribera-Chevremont
  - Expreso Imaginario, September 1982
    Centerfold on Blades, with lyrics, essays
  - TeVe Guía, 1982-9-4-1982-9-10
    Article, Efraín López Neris es el Productor de la Película "Pedro Navaja", by Juan Ortiz Jiménez
  - Jazz Magazine, April 1983
    Article, Dits et Cris de la Salsa, by Jeanne Brody, trans. Christian Gauffre
  - Istmo: La Estrella de Panama, [Oversized], 1983-5-29
    Centerfold poster of Blades
  - Jazz Magazine, June 1983
    Article, Dits et Cris de la Salsa: Rubén Blades, by Jeanne Brody
  - Artistas, August 1983
    Interview, Rubén Blades: ¡Dime la Verdad!, and article, Rubén Blades, El Sonoso Sonero Panameño, ¡Piensa Casarse! by Lourdes Calcagno
  - Latin N.Y., vol. 6, no. 8, August 1983
    Article, Salsa's Big Three, by Izzy Sanabria
  - Canto Popular, August 1983
    Blades mentioned in front matter and full page ad on back cover
  - Canto Popular, September 1983
    Articles, Blades x13, and Siembra Fecunda
  - TV Guía, 1983-9-7-1983-9-13
    Article, Se Viene la "Salsa!
  - Radiolandia 2000, 1983-9-9
    Article, Pedro Navaja se Pasea con Rubén Blades
  - Caras y Caretas, October 1983
    Article, "Esta Vaina Ya no es Como Antes", by Gabriela Borgna
  - Semana, 1983-10-25
    Article, Rubén Blades: Con Sabor, by Marcela Caldas
  - Madison Avenue, November 1983
    Advertisement on back inside cover featuring photo of Blades
  - Avance, [Oversized], 1983
    Interview, Rubén Blades
  - Latin N.Y., vol. 7, no. 3, March 1984
    Photo of Blades with Machito, caption, Salsa's Hottest Pair
  - People, vol. 21, no. 18, 1984-5-7
    Review of Blades' Buscando America
  - Billboard Magazine, [Oversized], 1984-5-26
    Advertising for Buscando America inside, for Beat Street on back cover
  - Ici New York, [Oversized], June 1984
    Article, Panama Rock, by David Hershkovits
  - Music Sound Output, 1984-6-1
    Article, Ruben Blades: Not Your Traditional Salsa Artist
  - El Pais Artes, 1984-6-2
    Article, La Música Latina de Rubén Blades, by Antonio Gómez
  - Rolling Stone, [Oversized], 1984-6-7
    Review of Buscando America
  - Dominical, 1984-6-10
    Article mentioning Blades' younger brother Roberto Blades, Farándula Todo, by Manuel Carvajal
  - BAM, [Oversized], 1984-6-15
    Article, Rubén Blades: Future Salsa, by Bill Forman
  - Claridad, [Oversized], 1984-6-22-1984-6-28
    Article, Buscando a America, by Raúl Leis
  - Latin N.Y., vol. 7, no. 7, July 1984
    Article, Rubén Blades: His New LP is a Scorcher, by Adela Lopez
  - Rockbill, July 1984
    Article, Rubén Blades - a Man of Convictions
  - Time (US Edition), 1984-7-2
    Article, The Keen Edge of Rubén Blades, by Jay Cocks
  - Time (International Edition), 1984-7-2
  - Record, July 1984
    Article, The Education of Rubén Blades (All Come to Look for America)
  - New York Daily News, [Oversized], 1984-7-22
    Cover photo and article, Tuning Up, by David Hershkovits
  - Džuboks (Yugoslav), August 1984
    Article, Ruben Blejds Osvaja Evropu
  - People Weekly, 1984-8-13
    Article, A Novelist's Eye, a Humanist's Heart, and a Hot Band…
  - Réplica, 1984-8-15
    Article, Rubén Blades: El Creador de "Pedro Navaja" Quiere Ser Presidente de Panamá, by José Luis Rubio
  - Domingo, [Oversized], 1984-9-30
    Cover photo and article, Un Hombre Llamado Navaja, by Guillermo Cabrera Infante
  - Down Beat, November 1984
    Review of Buscando America, by Howard Mandel
  - People, 1984-12-24-1984-12-31
    Blades featured in Picks and Pans
  - Musician, 1984-12-1
    Article, Rubén Blades and Willie Colón: The Beat Goes North
  - Creem, 1985-1-1
    Article, Ruben Blades: Hot Salsa
  - Time, 1985-1-5
    Blades' album, Buscando America listed in Music: Best of '84
  - Billboard Magazine, [Oversized], 1985-1-26
    Article New York: Salsa Losing Popularity to Ballads on City Airwaves, by Max Salazar
  - Record, March 1985
    Blades listed in album of the year poll
  - Americas, March-April 1985
    Interview, The Vision of Rubén Blades, by Robert A. Parker
  - Variety, [Oversized], 1985-4-3
    Film review, Crossover Dreams: Tale of Ambitious Salsa Musician
  - Saturday Review, June 1985
    Article, The Young Meteors
  - Galeria (arts supplement of El Nacional), [Oversized], 1985-6-9
    Article, Broadway, by Roberto Geronimo
  - Illustré: Swing and Sound, 1985-6-27
    Preview of Blade's performance at the Montreux Jazz Festival
  - New York, 1985-8-19
    Article, Hey, It's Rubén Blades - A Latin Star Makes His Move, by Pete Hamill
  - Spin, [Oversized], 1985-9-1
    Article, Blades Running
  - Newsweek, 1985-9-9
    Interview, Salsa with a Political Spin, by Bill Barol
  - Revista Nacional de Cultura, December 1985
    Special tribute issue of the journal dedicated to Panamanian journalist and writer Roque Javier Laurenza, 1910-1984
  - Wire [Great Britain], December 1985
    Article, "Ruben Blades: The Cutting Edge"; by Sue Steward, Issue 22
  - Musician, 1986-1-1
    Interview, A Crossover Dreamer and Latin Music Provocateur Makes His Move
  - The Rocket (Seattle, WA), [Oversized], January 1986
    Review of Escenas, by Bruce Need
  - Interview, [Oversized], April 1986
    Interview with Rubén Blades; Music issue
  - ASCAP in Action, Spring 1986
    Article, It's Rubén's Time, by Pete Hamill
  - Melody Maker, [Oversized], 1986-6-14
    On the cover, Rubén Blades the Panama Cat; inside, Panama Red
  - US, 1986-7-28
    Photo of Blades in article, Political Rock - Backstage at Amnesty
  - Playgirl, September 1986
    Photocopy of article, 10 Sexiest Men in America, by Patrick McGilligan
  - Monthly Film Bulletin, vol. 53, no. 635, December 1986
    Review of Crossover Dreams, by Verina Glaessner
  - Elle, 1987-1-1
    Article, Rubén Blades: Latin American Music Star Crosses Into the Mainstream and the Movies, by Enrique Fernandez
  - Jet, 1987-2-9
    Article, Richard Pryor: "I Wanted to Do 'Critical Condition'... I Needed to Make People Laugh"
  - Rolling Stone, no. 496 [Oversized], 1987-3-26
    Review of Agua de Luna, by Laura Fissinger
  - Rolling Stone [Oversized], 1987-4-23
    Article, Rubén Blades's Latin Revolution, in Twentieth Anniversary Issue
  - Cosmopolitan, 1987-5-1
    Article, Red Hot Right Now - Rubén Blades Salsa Star with a Mission
  - Scene [Oversized], 1987-6-4
    Article, Rubén Blades: American Original, by Marc Holan
  - Daily News Magazine [Oversized], 1987-6-21
    Cover text and photo: The Panama Kid: Rubén Blades Seizes His dream, and article, Can't Sit Still, by David Browne
  - The New York Times Magazine [Oversized], 1987-6-21
    Article, Rubén Blades: Up from Salsa
  - Now (Toronto) [Oversized], 1987-6-25-1987-7-1
    Cover photo and article, Rubén Blades' Militant Media, by Daryl Jung
  - Hispanic Business, July 1987
    Cover text and photo, Crossing Over: Rubén Blades in "The Milagro Beanfield War"
  - Americas 2001, November-December 1987
  - Rolling Stone, no. 518 [Oversized], 1988-1-28
    Photo of Blades on p. 7, and article, Paul Simon Hosts All Star Benefit Show, by Sheila Rogers
  - Rolling Stone, no. 522 [Oversized], 1988-3-24
    Article, English LP Due from Rubén Blades, by Fred Goodman
  - Newsweek on Campus, April 1988
    Reviews of The Milagro Beanfield War and Nothing But the Truth
  - People Weekly, 1988-4-4
    Review of the album Nothing But the Truth, by Eric Levin
  - Billboard Magazine [Oversized], 1988-4-9
    Cover advertisement for Nothing But The Truth
  - Music and Sound Output, May 1988
    Article, Partner In Crime, by Richard Gehr
  - Rock Express, vol. 12, no. 124 [Oversized], May 1988
    Article, No Quarter, by Kerry Doole
  - BAM LA [Oversized], 1988-5-6
    Article, A Man for All Seasons
  - NME - New Music Express [Oversized], 1988-5-14
    Interview, Whirling Blades, by Richard Grabel
  - Rolling Stone, no. 526 [Oversized], 1988-5-19
    Review of Nothing But the Truth, by David Browne
  - L.A. Style [Oversized], July 1988
    Article, Panamanian Pandemonium, by Gerrie Lim
  - Time, 1988-7-11
    Article, Of Ghosts and Magic, about the Sting album, Nothing But the Truth
  - Revista Centro de Bellas Artes, November 1988
    Article, Rubén Blades: "Antecedente"
  - Variety [Oversized], 1988-12-28-1989-1-3
    Concert review, Rubén Blades, Mongo Santamaria and Paquito D'Rivera at the Village Gate, New York
  - Jazz Hot, January 1989
    Article, Rubén Blades, by Noël Balen
  - The Cable Guide, 1989-3-1
    Article, Dead Man Out: Danny Glover and Rubén Blades Get Sent to Prison, by Eric Sherman
  - Movieline, October 1989
    Article, Cinco de Cinema, by Meredith Brody
  - Canales, vol. 17, no. 332, December 1989
    Blades included in list of short bios
  - Time, 1990-1-29
    Article, Profile: Rubén Blades, Singer, Actor, Politico, by Guy D. Garcia
  - Decada, May-June 1990
    Article, Rubén Blades: Murallas Invisibles, by Pituka Ortega de Heilbron
  - US, 1990-6-25
    Article, Global Warmer
  - Casino Magazine, November 1990
    Article, Rubén Blades
  - El Pais Semanal, año 15, no. 713, 1990-12-9
    Interview, "Mírenme, esto es un Latinoamericano, by Soledad Alameda
  - Letra Internacional, no. 21/22 [Oversized], Winter 1991
    Blades connection unknown
  - Farándula, año 33, no. 83, May 1991
    Full page back cover ad for Blades album
  - Farándula, año 33, no. 84, June 1991
    Photo of Blades
  - Farándula, año 33, no. 85, July 1991
    Article, Blades y sus Raíces Musicales
  - Pantalla 3, año 10, no. 101, July 1991
    Review of Mo' Better Blues
  - TV y Novelas, 1991-7-3
    Article, Rubén Blades: Entre la Musica y la Politica, by Gustavo Heloso
  - El Fin de Semana, 1991-7-12-1991-7-18
    Blades mention torn out
  - Cambio, 1991-7-15
    Interview, "Cuando Me Dedique a la Política Dejaré la Música", by Juan Manuel Bellver
  - Que y Donde, 1991-7-22-1991-7-28
    Cover Photo and article, Rubén Blades o el Compromiso del Artista, by Antonio Busquets
  - Gente, 1991-7-28
    Article, Rubén Blades: Lo Que Salva a la Salsa es que no la Controla la Industria USA, by Pedro Calvo
  - Entertainment Weekly, 1991-8-16
    Article, Crazy Love, by Ken Tucker
  - Los Angeles Times, TV Times, 1991-8-18
    Article, Getting 'Crazy' with Christine Lahti and Rubén Blades
  - Grammy Magazine, August 1992
    Cover article, When Worlds Converge: Artists Weigh the Impact of Mixing Genres in the '90s, by Bill Forman
  - Más, September 1992
    Article, Buscando la Pasión de América
  - Latin Beat, vol. 2, no. 10, December-January 1993
    Article, Willie 'El Trombonista' Colon, by Vernon Boggs
  - Momento, no. 72, May 1993
    Article, Panamá: El Fenómeno Papa Egoro, by Silvio Hernández
  - Hombres de Maíz, no. 12, June 1993
    Article, Rubén Blades: De los Escenarios de la Fama a la Política, by David Carrasco
  - Latin Beat, vol 3, no. 5, June-July 1993
    Article, Ricardo Betancourt: A 10 Year Photo Retrospective in Latin Music, by Rudolph Mangual
  - Hispanic, September 1993
    Article, Panama's Pride, by Irene Middleman Thomas
  - Latin Beat, November 1993
    Article, featured on cover, Rubén Blades: Otra Página
  - The New Republic, 1993-11-1
    Article, Slippery Blades, by Amy Wilentz
  - Harper's Bazaar, March 1994
    Article, Blades Runner
  - People Weekly, 1994-5-8
    Article, On the Move: Panama's Favorite Son
  - Spin [Oversized], May 1994
    Article about the Papa Egoro presidential campaign, Reality Check
  - Straight No Chaser, no. 27, Summer 1994
    Short article, Ruben Blades... the salseros failed bid for Panama's presidency, by Alex Webb
  - Latin Beat, vol 5, no. 6, August 1995
    Article, For the Love of Music: The Poorly Paid Latin Musician, by Frank Figueroa
  - Saludos Hispanos, October-November 1995
    Article in Spanish and English, Rubén Blades Master of Salsa and Jack of All Trades
  - San Juan, April 1977
    Cover text, photo and article, World Citizen, by P.J. Ortiz
  - Latin Beat, June-July 1997
    Article, Rubén Blades and his Cast of Characters, by Frank M. Figueroa
  - In Theater, 1998-1-2
    Article, Defending the Capeman, and articles on Marc Anthony and Ednita Nazario
  - Entertainment: Cards, Collectibles, Phone Cards and Price Guide, 1998-7-10
    Article, X-Files Franchise Moves from Tube to Silver Screen for Topps, by Kurt Samuels
  - Urban Latino, issue 22, 1999
    Article, Rubén Blades: Renaissance Man, by Rodrigo Salazar
  - Pirineos Sur, July 1999
    Article, Buscando América. Y In Eso Llegó Rubén, by Javier Losilla
  - Rhythm, issue 78, September 1999
    Cover text and photo: Americanos: Latino Life in the U.S., and article, Americanos: A Multimedia Project Illuminates the Latino Experience, by Larry Birnbaum
  - New York Times Magazine, 1999-10-17
  - LA Arts and Entertainment [Venice, CA], October 1999
    Interview, Sign of the Times
  - Viernes (El Nuevo Herald) [Oversized], 2000-7-13
    Cover photo and article, El Hombre que le Dio Luz a la Salsa, by Norma Niurka
  - People en Español, June-July 2002
    Article, Rubén Blades: Trovador de un continente, by Diana Molina
  - Pulse (Tower Records), September 2002
    Article, HOT HOT HOT! Fania Records and the Rise of Salsa
  - Pulse (Tower Records), October 2002
    Article, Rubén Blades Speaking a New Pop Language
  - Latin Beat, January 2003
    Interview, in English, Cuando el Mundo es el Barrio
  - Illinois Entertainer [Oversized], February 2003
    Interview with Lou Reed, Mundo
  - Latin Beat, February 2006
    Cover story and article, Fania is Back!, by Rudy Mangual
  - Agenda, April 2006
    Interview, in Spanish, Rubén Blades, memorias y retos..., by Amalia Aguilar Nicolau
  - Latin Beat, April 2006
    Cover Story on Ray Barretto
  - Rolling Stone, no. 1010 [Oversized], 2006-10-5
    Article, The Salsa Kings: Fania Records, the Greatest Latin Music Label of All, Opens the Vaults, by Peter Relic
  - Latin Beat, January 2007
    Story about Ray Baretto Tribute
  - People en Español, February 2007
    Article, Los Hispanos Más Influyentes
  - La Revista - El Nuevo Dia, 2008-6-8
    Cover article, 30 Años de Siembra, by Sara del Valle Hernández
  - Latin Beat, vol. 18, no. 8, October 2008
    Issue called, The Fania All Stars
  - Latin Beat, vol. 18, no. 9, November 2008
    Issue titled, Thirty Years after 'Siembra': Rubén Blades, Willie Colón, Jose Mangual, Jr., Jimmy Delgado, Eddie Montalvo
  - El Diario [Oversized], 2009-11-26
    Cover photo and article, Rubén Blades y los Seis del Solar: Vuelven a Nueva York, by Heriberto Gonzalez-Andino
  - New York Times [Oversized], 2009-1-28
    Article, A Salsa Star is Reborn After a Break for Politics, by Larry Rohter
  - New York Daily News [Oversized], 2011-2-23
    Article, Two Salsa Voices in Harmony, by Caroline González
  - New York Times Book Review, 2013-4-7
    Letter to the editor written by Blades, Whose Success?
- Series III. Publicity, promotional materials and programs, 1985-2014; 2 boxes; 2 boxes.
  Note: Promotional posters are included in Series VIII.
  - Subseries 1. Press kits, Box 1.
    The arrangement is chronological.
    - Crossover Dreams press kit, 1985; 2 folders.
      Film, 1985
      Black and silver Miramax pocketed folder; 5 photographs; Rubén Blades has leading role as Rudy Veloz.
    - Agua de Luna press kit, 1987; 1 folder.
      Sound recording, 1987